# rachel greene

phone: 206.618.6878 email: greenest@gmail.com portfolio: www.rachelgreenedesign.com

linkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/greenerachel

#### about me

I am a UX designer building off my career in architecture – exploring good design principles, understanding user flows, and embracing negative space- shifting my focus on the digital world and how it impacts the user.

tools

Sketch3, Axure, Invision, POP, Omnigraffle, Balsamiq, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Dreamweaver, CSS, HTML5, Revit, AutoCAD, SketchUp, Paper and Pen

skills

Information Architecture, Research, Prototyping, Usability Testing, Wireframes, Heuristic Evaluations, Design Specs, Teamwork, Communication, Leadership

languages

English (native), Spanish

#### education

#### **User Experience Immersive**

General Assembly Seattle, Washington

### **UX** Design

Career Foundry Online

## **Master of Architecture BS Architecture**

Washington State University Pullman Washington

#### fun fact

- 1. I'm Architect 10779 in the State of Washington.
- 2. I spend my free time with my husband and daughter.
- 3. I've lived in 4 countries.

experience

**UX** Designer Nov 2015 - Dec 2015

LoudBeacon

**UX** Designer Sept 2015- Dec 2015

General Assembly

**UX** Designer Aug 2014 - Sept 2015

Freelance Designer

Architect Aug 2012- May 2014

Boxwood

**Project Designer** Aug 2010 - Aug 2012

Stock & Associates

April 2008 - May 2009 **Project Designer** 

Jones & Jones

Nov 2007- April 2008 **Project Designer** 

PB Architects

**Municipal Development Volunteer** June 2005 - July 2007

Peace Corps El Salvador

select projects

LoudBeacon Mobile Application

skills: Leadership, Prototyping, Research, Wireframes, Information

Architecture, Design Specs

tools: Sketch3, Invision, Sketching, InDesign

FairWeather Camper

Web Application

skills: Research, Prototyping, Usability Testing, Wireframes, Heuristics

tools: Sketch3, Invision, Sketching

Festival Application

Mobile Application

skills: Leadership, Research, Prototyping, Usability Testing, Wireframes,

Heuristics, Communication, Design Specs

tools: Axure, Sketching, InDesign

**RGDesign** 

Portfolio Website

skills: Research, Prototyping, Usability Testing, Wireframes, Heuristics

tools: Sketching, sketch, HTML5, CSS

Epilog **Desktop Application** 

skills: Research, Wireframes, Heuristics, Communication

tools: Sketch3, Invision, Sketching